<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on SACHIN H S</title>
    <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on SACHIN H S</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Image Classification App</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Image Classification App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that uses the pre-trained VGG16 model from Imagenet to classify images. It allows users to upload an image and the app will provide a prediction of the most likely object or objects in the image, along with a confidence score. The VGG16 model is a convolutional neural network trained on millions of images, which enables it to recognize a wide variety of objects and scenes with high accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ML App</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;ML App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit-based application that allows users to perform end-to-end machine learning tasks with minimal coding. The app takes in user data and guides them through the process of selecting and training a model, evaluating its performance, and making predictions. Users can select from a variety of pre-built models, including popular algorithms such as Random Forest, XGBoost and Neural Network. The app has a built-in evaluation metric such as accuracy, which allows users to easily compare different models and select the best one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An SQL Queries App</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;SQL Queries App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the OpenAI API to provide users with a natural language interface for querying databases. The app allows users to input natural language questions, such as &amp;ldquo;What are the total sales for each product category?&amp;rdquo; and the app will generate the corresponding SQL query to retrieve the desired information. The OpenAI API uses advanced natural language processing techniques to understand the user&amp;rsquo;s question and generate the appropriate SQL query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank Note Authenticator</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-13/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Bank Note Authenticator App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the Random Forest Classifier algorithm to predict whether a banknote is authentic or not. The app allows users to input various characteristics of the banknote such as variance, skewness, curtosis, and entropy, and the app will predict whether the note is genuine or counterfeit. The Random Forest Classifier model is trained on a dataset of banknote characteristics and corresponding authenticity labels, which allows it to make accurate predictions for new data points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSV Viewer and Column Renamer</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This Streamlit app allows users to easily view and manipulate CSV files. The app features a file uploader that allows users to load a CSV file directly from their computer. Once uploaded, the app displays the contents of the CSV in a table format, making it easy to view and navigate the data. Additionally, users can rename columns and download the processed CSV file to their computer. This is useful for quickly making changes to large datasets without the need for additional software or programming knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Generator.</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Email Generator&amp;rdquo; streamlit app allows users to quickly and easily generate professional and personalized email content. Utilizing the OpenAI API, the app is able to understand the context of the user&amp;rsquo;s input and generate relevant and grammatically correct responses. This can save time and effort for users who frequently compose emails, such as business professionals and customer service representatives. The app also includes a built-in editor for users to review and make final adjustments to the generated email before sending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory data Analysis Application.</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the pandas profiling library to quickly and easily perform exploratory data analysis on any dataset. The app allows users to upload a CSV file and generate a comprehensive report of the dataset, including summary statistics, missing values, correlation, and other relevant information. The pandas profiling library is a powerful tool that automates the process of performing EDA, saving users time and effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Engineering App.</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Feature Engineering App&amp;rdquo; streamlit app streamlines the process of creating new features for machine learning models. With this app, users can easily extract, transform, and select features from their datasets. The app allows users to perform a wide range of feature engineering techniques such as scaling, normalization, and one-hot encoding. Additionally, it includes advanced feature selection methods like Lasso and Random Forest feature importances. This can save time and effort for data scientists and machine learning engineers who frequently work on feature engineering tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grammar Correction and Suggestion App</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Grammar Correction and Suggestion App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the power of ChatGPT and the OpenAI API to provide users with real-time grammar correction and suggestions for their written text. The app allows users to input any type of written text, including emails, articles, and social media posts, and quickly receive feedback on grammar errors, punctuation mistakes, and other language issues. Additionally, the app offers suggestions for improving the overall clarity and readability of the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LET&#39;S PREDICT YOUR MARKS.</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Marks Prediction App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the Linear Regression algorithm to predict the marks obtained in an exam based on the number of hours studied. The app allows users to input the number of hours studied, and the app will predict the expected marks based on a linear relationship established between the two variables. The Linear Regression model is trained on a dataset of student study hours and corresponding exam marks, which allows it to make accurate predictions for new data points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Diabetes</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Diabetes Prediction App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the Random Forest Classifier algorithm to predict whether a person has diabetes or not. The app allows users to input various health-related information such as blood pressure, glucose level, age, and BMI, and the app will predict the likelihood of the person having diabetes. The Random Forest Classifier model is trained on a dataset of patient information and corresponding diabetes labels, which allows it to make accurate predictions for new data points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salary Estimator</title>
      <link>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sachinhs04.github.io/SACHIN_H_S_PORTFOLIO_/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Salary Prediction App&amp;rdquo; is a Streamlit application that utilizes the Multiple Linear Regression algorithm to predict an individual&amp;rsquo;s salary based on various features such as years of experience, education level, and job type. The app allows users to input the relevant information and the app will predict the expected salary. The Multiple Linear Regression model is trained on a synthetic dataset of employee information, which allows it to make accurate predictions for new data points.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>